Tom Reeb

Philadelphia, PA | 215-290-2276 | Thomas.Reeb@gmail.com | https://tomreeb.com | linkedin.com/in/tomreeb

Summary

Seasoned technical leader with over 10 years' experience specializing in product development and engineering, cloud-native SaaS platforms, product roadmaps, departmental budgeting, and resource planning.

Skills Project Management Agile Software Development: Scrum and Kanban, Waterfall

Data Analytics Splunk, Prometheus, Grafana, Tableau, Elasticsearch, Kibana, Looker

Cloud Technologies Amazon Web Services, Openstack, Azure Automation Frameworks Bash, Shell, Python, Ansible, Terraform

Experience

Manager, Product Development and Engineering - Comcast

July 2016 - Present

Own the overall roadmap and development for multiple SaaS platforms that support the XfinityWiFi network. Develop and coordinate technological direction and strategy for software and platform engineering. Focus on driving quality of experience through data-driven process improvement and operational excellence. Core tech council lead; responsible for setting organization-wide standards with regards to software development workflows, continuous integration and continuous delivery strategies, cloud and container orchestration. Collaborate with senior leadership to forecast budgets and develop resource plans. Manage team of 10-14 Software and DevOps engineers developing SaaS platforms to support business objectives and serve millions of daily active subscribers.

- Led transformation of Captive Portal platform to improve user experience and easily on-board new subscribers generating over \$50M of revenue annually
- Launched redesigned Inventory Management System to streamline field operations workflows that led to increased throughput and reduced costs
- Refactored device provisioning platforms reducing the time for customer preference changes to take effect from twenty-four hours to less than one minute

Manager, IT Infrastructure - Coriell Institute for Medical Research

August 2013 - July 2016

Responsible for the technical direction and roadmaps of IT infrastructure and platforms for primary and remote offices. Led a team of engineers that support IT related business needs, enable efficiencies through technology, and drive infrastructure improvements to facilitate collaboration. Hands-on project manager and technical lead for all IT-related projects.

- Led various initiatives to promote collaboration through technology such as web & video conferencing implementation, conference rooms designed around connectivity, wireless and mobility enhancement
- Instituted and documented disaster recovery and business continuity plans built around a fault tolerant network re-architecture.
- Assisted senior leadership and scientific staff through RFP and bidding processes for research grants, which comprised the
 organizations main revenue source
- Reduced annual IT spend year over year through contract negotiations and operational improvements

Sr. Associate, IT Infrastructure Operations - The Hackett Group

July 2012 - August 2013

Lead infrastructure engineer on a distributed team responsible for building and maintaining private cloud infrastructure supporting business operations at 14 remote sites and two data centers globally. Managed operational support of customer facing SaaS portals, databases, and business analytics platforms. Participated in annual Sarbanes—Oxley compliance audits to review and update controls. Planned and led individual and team-based projects.

- Developed inventory asset management platform for corporate IT systems, servers, and end user devices
- Established and executed Disaster Recovery and Business Continuity plans essential to 24x7 global business operations
- Collaborated with business leads to develop and implement company-wide collaboration tools with a focus on security and
 protection of intellectual property

Network Administrator I - Philadelphia Housing Authority

March 2008 - July 2012

Network Administrator for a large government agency with 50+ remote office locations. Developed an operation IT inventory asset management platform consisting of 150 servers, 1,200 workstations, and over 250 laptops and mobile devices.

- Automated device provisioning, software deployment, and network security patches
- Managed projects to orchestrate large-scale hardware and software upgrades with appropriate user accept testing training seminars
- Developed project plans and led implementation of power management software leading to opex savings of over \$60,000 annually

Education

Drexel University
La Salle College High School

Bachelor of Science in Information Systems, Business Administration High School Diploma

2005 - 2010

2001 - 2005